elica.com 2017-07-06

# Privacy | Elica

Dear User, pursuant to art. 13, paragraph 1 of Italian Legislative Decree 196/2003 governing the protection of personal data (for brevity, hereinafter the “Code”), we inform you that the personal data you provide may be processed by ELICA pursuant to and in accordance with the aforementioned legislation. This privacy statement relates to all the services that can be accessed from elica.com.

## 1\. Types of data processed and purposes of processing.

Your personal data will be processed in compliance with your fundamental rights and freedoms and in respect of your dignity, with particular reference to confidentiality, personal identity and your right to the protection of your personal data, for the purpose of offering you effective use of elica.com.

### A) Browsing data

In the course of normal operation, the ICT systems and procedures involved in the running of this site automatically acquire certain items of personal data relating to the user’s browsing. These data are collected exclusively for the purpose of obtaining anonymous statistical information about the use of the site and to check that it is working properly.  
This category of data includes, by way of example:

  * •IP addresses of computers used by site-users for accessing the service; 

  * •number of accesses; 

  * •pages viewed; 

  * •date and time of access; 

  * •URL visited with the browser before viewing our page; 

  * •type of browser; 

  * •operating system used. 

### B) Data provided voluntarily by the user

The data provided freely and voluntarily by the user through the transmission of email to the addresses specified on this site will be acquired by Elica.  
In particular, in addition to the sender's email address, which is needed for the purpose of replying, Elica will acquire any other personal data to which transmitted email refers or contains.  
Data collected in this way will not be distributed or used for direct commercial or advertising purposes, and will be stored solely for the purposes of retaining correspondence.

### C) Cookies

Cookies consist of portions of code installed in the browser that assist the Owner in providing the service according to the purposes described. Some of the purposes for which the Cookies are installed may also require the User's consent.

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Strictly necessary cookie

These Cookies are necessary for the proper functioning of this Application and are used to store sessions and preferences.

#### device, device_type, has_js

Used to store preferences of the Application.

#### Drupal.session_cache.sid

Used to store the User session and keep the User logged in.

#### Google Analytics with anonymized IP (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users' IP addresses within Member States of the European Union or in other Contracting States to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the USA.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### AddThis (Addthis Inc.)

AddThis is a service provided by Clearspring Technologies Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of this Application.  
Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

#### Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://about.pinterest.com/privacy/)

#### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

#### Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google Inc.)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.  
If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

#### Instagram widget (Instagram, Inc.)

Instagram is an image visualization service provided by Instagram, Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)

### D) Web Beacons

The site does not use Web Beacons. A Web Beacon is an electronic image (e.g. a transparent GIF image consisting of a single pixel) located on a web page and used to monitor whether a certain page has been visited or not, and to compile statistics an cumulative data about the use of the web site. Web Beacons are normally used for the purpose of optimising the flow of web traffic.  
You can disable the use of Web Beacons by blocking the cookies associated with them.

### E) Referrers

ELICA may collect information by means of referrers and a range of environmental variables. A referrer consists of the data relating to the URL by means of which a user reached a given site, and which the user’s browser can automatically provide to ELICA.  
The environmental variables may include the domain name from which the user accessed [http://elica.com](http://elica.com/), the time of access to the site, the type of browser and operating system used, the address of the last site visited before accessing the ELICA site, the names of pages visited on [http://elica.com](http://elica.com/) and the address of the next site visited. All of the above information may be collected for the purpose of determining general trends and improving the quality of the service offered to site users. These data are totally anonymous, and if collected, are never associated with any personal data

### F) Data provided by telephone

Should you decide to contact our customer service, the latter will process the data you choose to give solely for the purpose of providing you with support regarding ELICA products.  
Data thus collected will not be distributed or used for direct commercial or advertising purposes, and will be retained exclusively for the aforementioned purposes.

## 2\. Communication of data

Your data may come to the attention of our employees, partners and dealers, who, in their capacity as appointees and/or processors, are authorised to process the data in pursuance of the purposes specified in this statement  
Your data may also come to the attention of third-party companies that provide Elica with ICT/information services. These parties may assume the role of data processors.  
Your data may not be disseminated without your express consent.  
Should you decide to contact our telephone support service, the data you choose to disclose will be processed by our customer service operators.

## 3\. Transfer of data abroad

Personal data may be transferred abroad, both inside and outside the European Union.

## 4\. Voluntary nature of data provision.

With the exception of the provisions specified above regarding browsing data, the provision of all other personal data by users of this site is optional and left entirely to the discretion of the user.  
Failure to provide personal data shall have no prejudicial consequences for the user.

## 5\. Rights of the data subject

Pursuant to art. 7 of the Code, we inform you that, as data subject, you are entitled to obtain confirmation of the existence or otherwise of personal data relating to you, even if they has not yet been recorded, and their disclosure in intelligible form.  
The data subject is entitled to be informed of:

  1. 1.the origin of the personal data; 

  2. 2.the purposes of and procedures for its processing; 

  3. 3.the logic applied in the event of processing with the aid of electronic devices; 

  4. 4.the identification details of the data controller, data processors and designated representative in accordance with article 5, paragraph 2; 

  5. 5.the parties or categories of party to which the personal data may be communicated or who may apprise themselves of it in their capacity as designated representative in the territory of the State, data processors or appointees. 

The data subject shall be entitled to obtain:

  1. 1.the updating or correction of his/her data, or the addition thereto should it be in his/her interest; 

  2. 2.the deletion, conversion into anonymous form or freezing of data processed in breach of the law, including data whose retention is not necessary in relation to the purposes for which the data were collected or subsequently processed; 

  3. 3.a declaration that the operations defined in a) and b) have been brought to the attention, including in relation to their content, of those parties to which the data were communicated or disclosed, unless fulfilment of this condition proves impossible or requires the use of resources manifestly disproportionate to the right protected. 

The data subject shall be entitled to object, either partially or as a whole:

  1. 1.for legitimate reasons, to the processing of personal data relating to him/her, even if pertinent to the purpose for which they were collected; 

  2. 2.to the processing of personal data relating to him/her for the purposes of sending advertising or direct sales material or commercial communications or conducting market research. 

The above rights may be exercised by simple request involving no formal procedures, including through an agent, to be sent directly to the data controller at [info@elica.com](mailto:info@elica.com).

## 6\. Data controller and processors

The data controller is ELICA, with registered office in Fabriano (AN), Via Ermanno Casoli 2, CAP 60044, Italy, [info@elica.com](mailto:info@elica.com)

The data processor for the ICT services connected with the site to which this statement pertains is IM*MEDIA Srl, with registered office in Palermo (PA), Via Generale Vincenzo Magliocco 27, CAP 90141, Italy, email: [info@immedia.net](mailto:info@immedia.net).
